Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
This G-Fighter is made up entirely
of the new Gundam parts.
We've had Ms. Sayla piloting it...
...and we've had no technical problems.
If we separate the G-Fighter
and insert Gundam in between...
...we get the G-Armor...
...which is a combination of the Gundam
with all the new parts.
The problem is, we haven't been able
to test a mid-air docking.
Ms. Sayla isn't used to it yet.
Well, excuse me.
It's okay.
But there's no problem separating
the parts from the Gundam in mid-air.
At this speed, I think we'll be able
to do it even during battle.
The laser sensor alignment
needs to be refined.
Sorry, I gotta go to the toilet.
Make it quick.
Sure.
Our main problems with its usage
are in these following areas...
The G-Sky is formed by adding the G-Parts'
rear engine to the Core Fighter...
...so it can be used as
a long-range fighter-bomber.
But it uses the bottom half of the Gundam...
...so while the G-Sky's in action,
the Gundam is disabled.
So we'd mostly use the
Easy form of the G-Sky.
It can use any Core Fighter from
the Guncannon or Guntank.
He's gotta be kidding.
Let's dock the G-Bull into the G-Armor.
These shields, right here.
The main goal of these new parts
is to strengthen the Gundam's armor.
But if you think about the moment
when it converts into the Gundam...
...you have to remove the shields.
So what we need to do is develop
a joint to link the two shields together.
And we'll also need at least twice
as many supply parts.
Otherwise, we'll be unable to make
the best use of our one Gundam.
Looks like they'll live on this ship
for the rest of their lives.
A Spy on Board
I understand.
I'll have them work on technical
improvements as soon as possible.
When the White Base's
engine maintenance is complete...
...you will head to Federation
headquarters in South America.
I will return to the frontlines
in Europe. That's all.
All rise! Salute!
I pray for your success.
And... give my regards
to those three little ones.
I wonder if Mr. Shiden is going to leave us.
Where is he gonna go?
How should any of us know that?
I think he really is leaving.
Yeah... I think so.
Repair it quickly.
Yes, sir!
Ask the Colonel!
Mr. Kai...
Mr. Kai...!
Where are you going?
It's inevitable. All those military formalities
just don't suit me at all.
Mr. Kai.
I can't say I like everything about you.
But we're comrades,
who have been through so much together!
I like the way you put that, Amuro.
Well, take care of yourself.
M-Mr. Kai!
Let him do as he likes.
But...
Hey, Mr. Bright.
If you push yourself too much,
you can't win battles.
And that's why I've decided to quit.
The Zeons are pushing themselves hard, too.
I guess I've just gone past my limits.
Mr. Kai!
Please take this along with you.
You should be able to sell it for some cash.
But that's your toolbox, isn't it?
You'll need money, no matter where you go.
Well, thanks.
I can't say I like everything about you either.
But, I appreciate it.
I'm glad you feel that way.
It's been a pleasure. Thanks for everything!
Are you really going?
Yeah! Stay alive, okay?
You also think he's a coward,
don't you, Mirai?
The second ship is carrying a Z'Gok...
...an amphibious heavy mobile suit.
They're extremely reliable.
But this ship only has one Gogg.
Good. Have them stop
the Trojan Horse from leaving.
Before the Trojan Horse leaves the dock,
I want to know where it's heading.
Sir! I've already got someone working on it.
Think I should start a hardware store?
Eh, Amuro?
Mr. Soldier!
Oh, it's you again.
You look like you've been
thrown off the warship.
Yeah, something like that.
You don't have a place to stay, do you?
Come stay at my house.
You mean it?
So there must be a catch, right?
No way.
I don't mind if it's only for a couple of days.
My name's Miharu.
I live with my little brother and sister.
You don't mind, do you?
So the three of you are hiding
in an abandoned house?
Yeah.
Welcome home, sis!
Welcome home!
Were you good?
Sure!
It's okay. He's gonna be our guest.
Hey, how do you do?
About the warship you were on...
Yeah?
It's quite something.
I guess so. You like ships?
Yeah, growing up by the sea.
Well, even though the White Base is a ship,
it's technically more of a space warship.
I see. It's a spaceship.
Right.
What?.
Just worrying about nothing.
You're probably tired.
Rest for a while, I'll go get you a blanket.
Huh?
Make yourself at home.
They seem well trained.
Listen. If he leaves the house,
you let me know right away, okay?
Mhm.
We understand.
This is just too bad.
Sorry to be a bother!
Not at all!
You know, the White Base
is leaving tonight.
Huh?
They're having issues with
the starboard engine.
If they took a hit in that spot,
the ship would likely be stuck here.
Mr. Kai...
Don't worry about it.
I know how you feel, having to take care
of your younger brother and sister.
Mr. Kai.
Captain.
There's a message from No. 107, sir.
She's in contact with
a Trojan Horse crew member.
Apparently, the Trojan Horse is having
problems with its starboard engine.
Understood.
Hmm...
Captain.
Yes?
Exactly where is No. 107 situated?
The same harbor as the Trojan Horse.
While we attack with the Gogg...
...have No. 107 sneak aboard
the Trojan Horse.
Huh?
I would like to cover all possibilities.
All right?
Sir!
And if you do succeed,
I will expedite your return to Zeon.
I'd appreciate it.
Please return to the Mad Angler, Captain.
I'll pull this one off.
Thank you. I am counting on you.
Have the Mad Angler prepare for backup.
Yes!
Ship No. 2, launch Z'Gok!
Everything's going smoothly.
This machine suits me much
better than the Gogg.
We've lost response from Area 29.
A mobile suit?
Unknown. It's faster than the previous ones.
Tell the crew to stand by to intercept!
Take off at once?! It'll take us a little longer.
Send out the Guncannon and Guntank!
How about the G-Fighter or G-Sky?
Well?
The voltage is a little irregular, but it's fine.
Okay!
The enemy is using Freeze Gel
so you can't pursue them?
It's our job to get past it and destroy them!
Prepare to fire anti-submarine missiles!
Activate the harbor's defenses
and synchronize sonar!
We will begin our attack on the enemy
at the exact moment the Z'Gok reaches land.
Connolly, use that diversion to get to shore.
CC2 received from Callahan
in the Z'Gok!
Right! Launch the backup Gogg
and then surface!
Launch Connolly's boat!
Is the dock's gate okay?
Just break through it.
It'll be no problem with the armor on this.
Easy for you to say.
Has the Guntank already left?
Ah, no. The shaft isn't operating properly.
Oh.
The repairs are done, so please get going!
Thank you very much!
Gundam taking off!
Ms. Sayla!
The Gundam will ride on top!
Roger!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
An air raid?
The White Base is being attacked?
It seems too soon
if Miharu informed Zeon herself.
Where did your sister go?
Sh-She'll be back in no time.
Y-Yeah, she went shopping.
Hmm... Did she really?
Uh... It's the truth!
Okay, I'll believe you.
Whatever you say...
It looks like they're attacking from the sea.
Gimme back my bicycle!
It's for military use, you'll get it back later!
Greetings! Are you in a big hurry?
Huh? You're...?
Ah, no! No, I'm not in any hurry, no.
Why did you call me out to a place like this?
I'm not used to this...
I didn't expect someone like you.
Here. There's money in this.
Your orders are to infiltrate the Trojan Horse
and find out where they're heading to.
How?
Figure that out for yourself.
Just sneak in by any means necessary.
There's a lot here...
You'll do it, won't you?
I hear there'll be more money in it
if you succeed. Here.
In this bag you'll find
a Federation Forces uniform...
...and the captain's letter.
I understand. I'll do it.
I have to do something to feed my family.
That's great. Well, I gotta go.
Here they come.
Judging from the silhouette,
it looks like the Gundam and a fighter.
Tell the forward Gogg to start attacking!
Prepare for anti-air combat!
Ms. Sayla! Please be careful!
There might be more than one ship.
Roger.
I'll attack the closest submarine
with the G-Fighter.
Welcome home, sis!
Were you afraid?
We were fine.
How's he doing?
He took his stuff and left a while ago.
Did he say anything?
He said, "Best of luck."
Yeah.
Best of luck...?
Mr. Kai...
Now, listen, you two...
Big Sis has to go to work now.
I could be gone for a bit longer
this time, okay?
Use this money carefully while I'm gone.
Never tell anyone where the money is.
Yeah, we know that!
When I'm done with this job, let's go
someplace where there's no war, okay?
All three of us...
You have to be patient.
I know how strong you two are.
We'll be okay.
Sis, you have the same nice smell
just like Mommy.
I'm sorry I made you remember.
A mobile suit is approaching
from the rear at 4 o'clock, sir!
What's wrong, Hayato?!
Launch the Guncannon!
I'm leaving now! Is the beam rifle ready?!
Hayato! Guncannon, launching!
It's got nothing to do with me now.
All that shooting and exploding.
C'mon! Now! Take this!
This guy's too accurate with his shooting.
So that's the infamous Gundam!
Well, it doesn't measure up to the rumors!
It doesn't concern me...
But... you know...
Dammit!
Why am I worrying about
the White Base after all those?!l
Coward!
Yeah... maybe I really am a coward.
Not the same trick again!
Serves you right!
Ms. Sayla! How's the battle going for you?!
Amuro! Please return!!
A mobile suit is attacking Hayato's
Guncannon over at the harbor.
This is Sayla in the G-Fighter.
I've got an anti-submarine attack plane
backing me now. So I'm okay.
Anyway, those guys are so slow...
it's impossible for me to sit back and watch!
Stop! I'm with the military! Stop!
Come to the base to pick it up later. Okay?
The Guntank... where's the Guntank?
There it is! What's it doing here?!
Oh, Mr. Kai! Please use it!
We just finished the repairs on its shaft!
Mr. Hayato's in the cannon now!
Well, I guess I have to.
I... I'm not gonna let you get any closer!
He's persistent. In that case...!
I'll tear you apart!
Oh no! I've taken so much damage,
there's no power left!
What? A tank?
I won't let you get away with this!
Okay. I'll lure the tank into the water
and take care of it out there.
I've had it with you!
So you wanna fight underwater
where you've got the advantage?
Sayla here. I sank the enemy ship!
It's coming!
I guess this one is the real Gundam,
but I'll finish it off!
Don't underestimate me!
You won't escape!
Here he comes...!
The remaining ship has retreated!
All right! Check all sections!
As soon as we're done with
the engine maintenance, we're taking off.
Yo!
Well, Amuro.
I was told your toolbox isn't worth a dime.
Is that so...
Oh, hello, Kai. Welcome back.
Hi, Ms. Sayla.
I couldn't stand watching you all struggle!
Right, Hayato?
Sure, whatever you say.
It looks like Spy No. 107
made it on board the Trojan Horse...
However the enemy did manage to sink
one Gogg and one Z'Gok.
Hm. That sounds about right.
That's Boone's problem.
Have him make arrangements
to contact our spy.
Sir!
Later that night...
...the White Base left the demolished town...
...with a spy on board.
Char's relentless pursuit
shows no signs of letting up.
As they face many dangers...
...Kai and Miharu's growing friendship
comes to a tragic end.
Who could possibly speak the words...
"Miharu, rest in peace"?
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Across the Atlantic Ocean.
Next Time
Across the Atlantic Ocean
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...